<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Terry Beyak's blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://terrybeyak.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://terrybeyak.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-03T11:04:09-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://terrybeyak.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Terry Beyak]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I Don't Know]]></title>
    <link href="http://terrybeyak.github.io/blog/2015/01/03/what-i-dont-know/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-03T10:40:57-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://terrybeyak.github.io/blog/2015/01/03/what-i-dont-know</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I take very seriously the adage that the first step towards wisdom is admitting that you do not know. I consider myself a relatively new programmer; moreover, my educational path was non-standard, and as such, there&rsquo;s a lot I do not know about programming, software, computers, and the development process. Lastly, and perhaps most importantly, I have yet to hear of a Theory of Introspection, i.e. a replicable system for identifying gaps in one&rsquo;s knowledge, and filling them.</p>

<p>The closest thing I have heard of, is writing. So here I am, blogging about what I know, and do not know, about programming and web development. In so doing, my hope is to write about my continuing discovery process of the things would like to learn. I&rsquo;ll be describing what I think I know, and what I still don&rsquo;t yet.</p>

<p>My suspicion is that some people will balk at the notion of admitting ignorance. It&rsquo;s not done often in our culture; the trends towards self-branding ego stroking are too strong. Moreover, am I putting my weaknesses on display for the world to ruthlessly mock? Yes possibly. But here we are.</p>

<p>And here we go.</p>

<p>Some things about which I don&rsquo;t know, but would like to know more, are as follows (in no particular order):</p>

<ol>
<li>AngularJS</li>
<li>iOS Development</li>
<li>Go</li>
<li>Machine Learning</li>
<li>JSON-RPC</li>
<li>Bitcoin</li>
<li>Macroeconomics</li>
<li>Cosmology</li>
</ol>


<p>The things I know a little bit about, but would like to get much better at, are these:</p>

<ol>
<li>Drupal</li>
<li>Ruby on Rails</li>
<li>Git</li>
<li>BackboneJS</li>
<li>the DNS system</li>
</ol>


<p>These two lists could go on quite comedically, but I&rsquo;ll stop there. The next post will likely be a little bit about Git.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
