<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Css | Terry Beyak's blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://terrybeyak.github.io/blog/categories/css/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://terrybeyak.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-27T21:58:51-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://terrybeyak.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Terry Beyak]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flexbox Is Awesome]]></title>
    <link href="http://terrybeyak.github.io/blog/2015/03/28/flexbox-is-awesome/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-28T10:58:22-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://terrybeyak.github.io/blog/2015/03/28/flexbox-is-awesome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It burbled to my consciousness as if waking from a dream. CSS3 <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Guide/CSS/Flexible_boxes" title="CSS3 Flexbox">Flexbox</a> is a tool meant for the modern age of web design, at least as my company understands it.</p>

<p>So much of this CSS tool works the way I want a tool to work: I want to set a container element, like a div, and define <em>generally</em> how its nested elements should behave. Then, I want to, for each item, define CSS rules to describe specifically how it should act.</p>

<p>This is how front-end web developers think. We don&rsquo;t think in terms of mathematical dryness like &ldquo;margin: 5px 0 10px 0;&rdquo;. We want to say something like, &ldquo;ok all you list-items, start out pushed up against the right side of your container, and extend leftward as far as you can go.&rdquo;</p>

<p>P.S. That would be ul { display: flex; justify-content: flex-end; }</p>

<p>It strikes me that the irony is, it took a few decades in order for the W3C to define how developers and designers have been thinking this whole time. It makes me wonder if it was a matter of browser sophistication, or it took that governing body a while to figure out how best to implement it.</p>

<p>The matter of exploring how a governing body of a technology or suite of software operates ought to be the subject of another post.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
